塔迪斯怎么了 好像有点不舒服
I wonder what's wrong with her. She's sort of queasy.
消化不良 她似乎不想着陆
Indigestion. Like she didn't want to land.
如果你觉得会有麻烦
If you think there's gonna be trouble,
我们随时可以回到里面 飞到其他地方
we could always get back inside and go somewhere else.
看样子我们停在橱柜里了 走吧
I think we've landed inside a cupboard. Here we go.
开启15号门
Open door 15.
似乎是某种基地
Some sort of base.
月球基地 海洋基地 太空基地
Moon base, sea base, space base.
使用工具套件拼装起来的
They build these things out of kits.
幸好我们在室内
Glad we're indoors.
外面听上去有风暴
Sounds like a storm out there.
开启16号门
Open door 16.
人类的设计 你们对套件真是情有独钟
Human design, you've got a thing about kits.
这里是像平板包装的衣柜那样拼装成的
This place was put together like a flat-pack wardrobe,
不过更大 也更容易
only bigger and easier.
开启17号门
Open door 17.
噢 是个避难基地
Oh, it's a sanctuary base!
关闭17号门
Close door 17.
外太空探索 我们走得真远
Deep-space exploration. We've gone way out.
你听那个
And listen to that.
下面 有人在钻井
Underneath. Someone's drilling.
欢迎来到地狱
"Welcome to hell."
噢 没那么糟吧
Oh, it's not that bad.
不 在那儿
No, over there.
等等
Hold on.
上面写着什么
What does that say?
奇怪 无法翻译
That's weird. It won't translate.
可是塔迪斯不是能翻译一切吗 包括文字
But I thought the Tardis translated everything, writing as well.
我们应该看到英语  - 没错
I should see English. - Exactly.
如果无法翻译 那意味着
Now if that's not working, then it means...
这些文字很古老
this writing is old.
非常古老
Very old.
无法想像的古老
Impossibly old.
我们应该找找这儿的负责人
We should find out who's in charge.
我们进入了连塔迪斯也未知的世界 这趟可不太妙
We've gone beyond the reach of the Tardis' knowledge. Not a good move.
如果有人在找…
And if someone's looking for...
是的 你好
Right, hello. Sorry.
抱歉 我是说 基地很漂亮
Sorry. I was just saying, nice place.
我们必须喂食
We must feed.
什么
You gotta what?
我们必须喂食
We must feed.
我想它们说的是我们
Yeah, I think they mean us.
我们必须喂食…
We must feed.
我们必须喂…你们
We must feed...you,
如果你们饿了的话
if you are hungry.
什么
Sorry?
抱歉
We apologise.
电磁波影响了语言系统
Electromagnetics have interfered with speech systems.
你们想要点吃的吗
Would you like some refreshment?
开启18号门
Open door 18. Um...
什么情况
What the hell?
你们怎么…
How did...
船长
Captain,
你不会相信这个的 有人来了
you're not gonna believe this. We've got people.
不知从哪来的 真人
Out of nowhere. I mean, real people.
我是说两个活生生的人
I mean... Two living people
正站在我面前
just standing here right in front of me.
别傻了 不可能
Don't be stupid, that's impossible.
你对他俩说去吧
I suggest telling them that.
你们这里是一个太空基地
But you're a sort of space base.
你们肯定不时地会有访客 怎么会不可能
You must have visitors now and then. It can't be that impossible.
你是说你不知道这是哪儿
You telling me you don't know where you are?
一无所知 这样更有趣
No idea. More fun that way.
各位归位 扣上安全带 我们有情况
Stand by, everyone. Buckle down. We have incoming,
非常猛烈
and it's a big one.
0.5级震荡即将来袭
Quake 0.5 on its way.
这边走 马上
Through here. Now.
快 走吧 行动
Quickly, come on! Move!
向前走 赶紧
Move it! Come on!
继续走 快点
Keep moving! Come on!
继续走
Keep moving!
哦 天哪 你是说真的
Oh, my God, you meant it.
是人 看哪 是真人
People! Look at that, real people.
没错 万岁
That's us. Hurray!
百分之百真人
Yeah, definitely real.
我叫洛斯
My name's Rose,
洛斯·泰勒 这是博士
Rose Tyler, and this is the Doctor.
拜托
Come on,
肯定是氧气供应脱机了
the oxygen must be offline.
我们产生幻觉了 他们不可能…
We're hallucinating, they can't be...
不 是真的
No, they're real.
行了 现在正在警报中
Come on, we're in the middle of an alert.
丹尼 系好安全带 震荡马上就要来了
Danny, strap up, the quake's coming in.
离撞击还有30秒
Impact in 30 seconds.
抱歉 你们两位 不管你们是谁
Sorry, you two, whoever you are,
请牢牢抓紧
just hold on. Tight.
抓什么
Hold on to what?
任何东西 随便 只要抓紧
Anything, I don't care, just hold on.
怪奇 都抓紧了吗
Ood, are we fixed?
非常感激您在危急时刻的关爱
Your kindness in this emergency is much appreciated.
这颗行星叫什么
What's this planet called anyway?
别傻了 它还没有名字
Don't be stupid. It hasn't got a name.
它怎么会有名字
How could it have a name?
你们真的不知道吗
You really don't know, do you?
来了…冲击
And impact!
噢 这也不算太糟…
Oh, well. That wasn't so bad...
结束了
Okay, that's it.
大家没事吧
Everyone all right?
回答我 艾达
Speak to me! Ida?
没事
Yeah.
丹尼  - 没事
Danny? - I'm fine.
托比  - 很好
Toby? - Yeah, fine.
斯古蒂  - 没有损伤
Scooti? - No damage.
杰佛逊  - 没事
Jefferson? - Check!
我们很好 谢谢 不用担心我们
We're fine, thanks, fine. Yeah, don't worry about us.
地面塌陷
Surface caved in.
我把震荡转移到了五至八号贮藏库
I deflected it onto Storage 5 through 8.
它们全完了
We've lost them completely.
托比 去查查发射器连接
Toby, go and check the rocket link.
那里不是我负责的
That's not my department.
照我说的做 好吗
Just do as I say, yeah?
氧气稳定
Oxygen holding.
室内重力级别 56.6
Internal gravity at 56.6.
我们应该没事了
We should be okay.
别担心地震 那是…
Never mind the earthquake, that's...
那场真是好一场风暴
That's one hell of a storm.
那是什么 飓风吗
What is that, a hurricane?
飓风需要大气才能形成
You need an atmosphere for a hurricane.
外面没有空气 完全真空
There's no air out there. It's a complete vacuum.
那么 是什么在摇晃屋顶
Then what's shaking the roof?
你没开玩笑吧
You're not joking.
你们真的不知道
You really don't know.
自我介绍一下
Well, introductions.
顺便一提 就像古人说的
FYI, as they said in the olden days.
我是艾达·斯科特 科学指挥官
I'm Ida Scott, Science Officer.
扎克瑞·克罗斯·弗雷姆 代理船长
Zachary Cross Flane, Acting Captain, sir.
杰佛逊先生 你们见过了 负责安全
You've met Mr. Jefferson, he's Head of Security.
伦理学委员会的 丹尼·巴托克
Danny Bartock, Ethics Committee.
不像听起来那么无聊
Not as boring as it sounds.
刚离开的是 托比·泽德 考古学家
And that man who just left, that was Toby Zed, Archeology,
这是 斯古蒂·曼尼斯特 新生训练员
and this... is Scooti Manista, Trainee Maintenance.
这里…
And this...
这里是家
This is home.
打起精神
Brace yourselves.
此情此景是会使许多人发疯的
The sight of it sends some people mad.
那是黑洞
That's a black hole.
这不可能
But that's impossible.
我提醒过你
I did warn you.
我们正站在黑洞之下
We're standing under a black hole.
在轨道上
In orbit.
不可能
We can't be.
你自己看看 我们就在轨道上
You can see for yourself. We're in orbit.
但这不可能
But we can't be.
这块岩石就在黑洞同步轨道上缓慢运行
This lump of rock is suspended in perpetual geostationary orbit around that black hole,
不会被吸入
without falling in.
发表意见
Discuss.
这很糟糕 是吗
And that's bad, yeah?
"糟糕"不足以形容
Bad doesn't cover it.
黑洞是死去的恒星
A black hole's a dead star.
一直不停地往里坍缩
It collapses in on itself, in and in and in,
直到密度高得难以置信
until the matter's so dense and tight,
它便开始吞噬周围的一切
it starts to pull everything else in, too.
宇宙中没有物质能够逃脱
Nothing in the universe can escape it.
光 重力 时间
Light, gravity, time,
一切都只会被拽进去
everything just gets pulled inside
被压碎
and crushed.
所以他们不能环绕它运行
So they can't be in orbit?
我们早就应该被吞噬了
We should be pulled right in.
我们早该死了
We should be dead.
但没有
And yet,
我们还在这里
here we are.
超越了物理规律
Beyond the laws of physics.
欢迎来到这里
Welcome on board.
可是如果外面没有大气 那是什么呢
But if there's no atmosphere out there, what's that?
破碎的星星
Stars breaking up.
气云
Gas clouds.
这儿有一整个太阳系
We have whole solar systems
在我们头顶分崩离析
being ripped apart above our heads,
在被黑洞吞噬之前
before falling into that thing.
比风暴糟一点 是吗
So, a bit worse than a storm, then.
就一点点 没错
Just a bit. just a bit, yeah.
托比
Toby.
是谁
Who's that?
丹尼
Danny?
关闭一号门
Close door 1.
发射器链接正常
The rocket link's fine.
这个黑洞的官方编号是 K37 Gem 5
That's the black hole, officially designated K37 Gem 5.
在 Veltino 的手稿中
In the scriptures of the Veltino,
这颗行星被称为 Krop Tor
this planet is called Krop Tor,
意为"苦果"
the bitter pill.
而黑洞被描述为一个强大的恶魔
And the black hole is supposed to be a mighty demon
企图吞噬整个星球
who was tricked into devouring the planet
结果却一口吐了出来
only to spit it out
因为它有剧毒
because it was poison.
"苦果" 我喜欢
The bitter pill. I like that.
我们走得好远
We are so far out.
迷失在宇宙漂流之中
Lost in the drifts of the universe.
你们怎么来到这里的
How did you even get here?
飞进来的 你看
We flew in. You see...
这颗行星产生了一个引力场
this planet's generating a gravity field.
我们不知道其原理 毫无头绪
We don't know how, we've no idea,
但是 它不断与黑洞保持恒量平衡
but it's kept in constant balance against the black hole.
引力场延伸至那里
And the field extends out there
就像一个漏斗
as a funnel,
一个独特的引力漏斗 延伸至宇宙空间
a distinct gravity funnel reaching out into clear space.
这就是我们进来的路
That was our way in.
你们顺着那里飞进来的
You flew down that thing?
就像过山车
Like a roller coaster.
按理说 飞船早就该解体了
By rights, the ship should've been torn apart.
船长牺牲了
We lost the captain,
所以由我代理
which is what put me in charge.
你做得很好
And you're doing a good job.
情势所迫 只得如此
Yeah, well. Needs must.
一旦那个引力漏斗关闭 就没有出路了
But if that gravity funnel closes, there's no way out.
我们以猜测这些为乐
Oh, we have fun speculating about that.
是啊 真会挑词 以此为"乐"
Oh, yeah. That's the word, "fun".
但维持这样的引力场 需要消耗非常巨大的能量
But that field would take phenomenal amounts of power, I mean...
不只是巨大 是不可计量的能量
Not just big, but off the scale.
我能看看吗
Can 1...?
当然 请自便
Sure, help yourself.
您的饮料
Your refreshment.
好的 谢谢你
Oh, yeah, thanks. Thank you.
谢谢 抱歉 你叫什么
I'm sorry, what was your name?
我们没有名字
We have no titles.
我们是一个群体
We are as one.
它们叫什么
Erm, what are they called?
拜托 你从哪儿来的
Oh, come on. Where have you been living?
我们每人都有一个
Everyone's got one.
显然我没有 它们是什么
Well, not me. So, what are they?
它们是"怪奇"
They're the Ood.
怪奇
The Ood?
The Ood.
嗯 好"怪奇"的名字
Well, that's Ood.
很怪奇 但也很能干
Very Ood. But handy.
他们负责采矿 和所有钻井工作
They work the mineshaft, all the drilling and stuff.
监管和维护工作
Supervision and maintenance.
他们天生如此
They're born for it.
低等奴隶种族
Basic slave race.
你们用奴隶
You've got slaves?
别说了 她是那类人 怪奇的朋友
Don't start. She's like one of that lot, Friends of the Ood.
也许我就是
Well, maybe I am, yeah.
什么时候起人类需要奴隶了
Since when do humans need slaves?
怪奇一族是自愿的
But the Ood offer themselves.
如果你不命令他们做事
If you don't give them orders,
它们会日渐消瘦最终死亡
they just pine away and die.
真的吗 你们喜欢被使唤
Seriously? You like being ordered about?
那是我们唯一的渴求
It is all we crave.
为什么呢
Why is that, then?
我们的生活除此别无其他
We have nothing else in life.
我以前也这么认为
Yeah, well, I used to think like that.
很久以前
Long time ago.
好了 你们看
There we go. Do you see?
要产生引力场和引力漏斗
To generate that gravity field and the funnel,
必须有一个能量源
you'd need a power source
每六秒产生六的六次方次的反向自推力
with an inverted self-extrapolating reﬂex of six to the power of six every six seconds.
好多六啊
That's all the sixes.
而这是不可能的
And it's impossible.
我们花了两年才能算出
It took us two yea rs to work that out.
我很厉害的
I'm very good.
但那正是我们来这里的原因
But that's why we're here.
这个能量源就在岩石下十英里深处
This power source is ten miles below, through solid rock.
零点 我们正进行地下钻探 希望能发现它
Point 0. We're drilling down to try and find it.
放射强度超过90斯达
It's giving off readings of over 90 Statts on the Blazen Scale.
我们可以改革现代科学
It could revolutionise modern science.
我们可以用它加快帝国发展
We could use it to fuel the empire.
或挑起一场战争
Or start a war.
它埋葬在我们脚下
It's buried beneath us.
在黑暗中 等待着
In the darkness, waiting.
你是干什么的
What's your job?
首席戏剧制造家
Chief dramatist?
不管下面是什么 绝不是自然现象
Well, whatever it is down there, it's not a natural phenomenon.
这颗星球上曾经有生命
This planet once supported life,
万古以前 甚至在人类学会直立行走之前
aeons ago, before the human race had even learnt to walk.
我看见了墙上的文字 是你写的吗
I saw that lettering written on the wall, did you do that?
我从钻井发现的残片上临摹下来的
I copied it from fragments we found unearthed by the drilling,
但是无法翻译
but I can't translate it.
是的 我也不行
No, neither can I.
这说明了一些问题
And that's saying something.
曾经存在着某种文明
And there was some form of civilization.
他们隐瞒了什么
They buried something.
现在它重现了
Now, it's reaching out.
召唤着我们
Calling us in.
所以你们就来了
And you came.
我们怎么能不来
How could we not?
所以 归根结底 你们为什么来这儿
So, when it comes right down to it, why did you come here?
你们为什么这样做 为什么
Why did you do that? Why?
我来告诉你
I'll tell you why.
因为它就在那里 太棒了
Because it was there. Brilliant!
抱歉 呃 扎克 是吗
Excuse me. Zack, wasn't it?
没错
That's me.
站着别动 我要拥抱一下你
Just stand there 'cause I'm gonna hug you,
可以吗
is that all right?
有何不可
Suppose so.
好的 来吧
Here we go. Coming in.
人类 你们真是太惊人了
Human beings. You are amazing.
谢谢
Thank you.
不用谢
Not at all.
不过除此之外 你们真是疯了
But apart from that, you're completely mad.
你们应该整理包裹 登上飞船逃命去
You should pack your bags, get back on that ship and fly for your lives.
说得容易 你们究竟怎么来的
You can talk. How the hell did you get here?
我有一个…
Oh, I've got this...
这...飞船 很难解释 说出现就出现的
This ship... It's hard to explain, it just sort of appears.
可以给你看 我们把它停在走廊...
We can show you, we parked down the corridor from...
叫什么 生活区
What's it called? Habitation
三号
Area 3? 3.
你是说六号贮藏库
Do you mean Storage 6?
有点像橱柜 是的
It was a bit of a cupboard, yeah.
六号贮藏室 可你说…
Storage 6? But you said...
你说…
You said...
你说五号至八号贮藏室…
You said Storage 5 to 8.
怎么了 出什么事了
What is it? What's wrong?
开启19号门
Open door 19.
关闭19号门
Close door 19.
快点 拜托
Doors, come on!
开启17号门
Open door 17.
开启15号门
Open door 15.
16号门无法使用
Open door 16.
别这样
It can't be!
出什么事了 怎么了
What's wrong? What is it?
博士 塔迪斯在里面 出什么事了
Doctor, the Tardis is in there. What's happened?
塔迪斯不见了
The Tardis is gone.
16号门无法使用
Door 16 out of commission.
那次地震
The earthquake.
这个区域塌陷了
This section collapsed.
但塔迪斯肯定在外面某个地方
But it's got to be out there somewhere.
往下看
Look down.
地面塌陷
The ground gave way.
塔迪斯一定落在地心深处
My Tardis must have fallen down into the heart of the planet.
你的钻头在朝同样的方向钻探
You've got robot drills heading the same way.
我们不能改变钻探方向
We can't divert the drilling.
可我需要我的飞船 它是我的全部
But I need my ship! It's all I've got.
真的 我的唯一
Literally, the only thing.
博士 我们的资源只够挖一个
Doctor, we've only got the resources to dig one
直达能量源的中心轴 就这样
central shaft down to the power source and that's it.
不能转向 不能分心 没有例外
No diversions, no distractions, no exceptions.
你的飞船丢了
Your machine is lost.
我只能载你一程 如果我们能离开这儿的话
All I can do is offer you a lift, if we ever get to leave this place.
就这样 没得商量
And that is the end of it.
我会安排你值勤
I'll put you on the duty roster.
我们需要人洗衣服
We need someone in the laundry.
开启一号门
Open door 1.
关闭一号门
Close door 1.
我把你困在这儿了
I've trapped you here.
不 别担心我
No, don't worry about me.
好吧 我们在一颗不可能的行星上
Okay, we're on a planet that shouldn't exist,
运行在黑洞轨道上
underneath a black hole
没有出路
and no way out.
我改变主意了 担心一下我吧
Yeah, I've changed my mind. Start worrying about me.
进入夜晚模式
Entering night shift.
您选择的换班音乐是
Your chosen track for transition is
拉威尔的《波莱罗舞曲》
Ravel's 30mm.
完成了
All finished.
正赶回基地
Heading back inside.
侍者 γ-10
Server Gamma 10.
侍者 γ-11
Server Gamma 11.
侍者 γ-12
Server Gamma 12.
托比
Toby.
我能看见你
I can see you.
丹尼 是你吗
Danny, is that you?
这一点也不好玩
It's not funny, all right?
丹
Dan?
我在工作呢 丹尼
I'm trying to work, Daniel.
是你的话 别再玩了好吗
If that's you, Dan, can you just stop it?
丹尼 查看一下怪奇居住区的温度
Danny, check the temperature in Ood Habitation.
那儿的室温似乎上升了
It seems to be rising.
请自便 只是别吃绿的
Help yourself, just don't have the green.
和蓝的
Or the blue.
给我一点那个 谢谢
Um, a bit of that, thanks.
想加一点酱汁吗
Would you like sauce with that?
我想尝尝 好吧
I'll have a go, yeah.
我也做过这种工作
I did that job once.
我以前是女服务生
I was a dinner lady.
我不是说你是女生
Not that I'm calling you a lady.
我不知道 你没准是呢
Although, I don't know, you might be.
你们有工资吗 他们给钱吗
Do you actually get paid, though? Do they give you money?
怪兽和它的大军 即将从深渊崛起
The Beast and his armies shall rise from the Pit
并向上帝宣战
to make war against God.
什么
I'm sorry?
抱歉 我是说 请慢慢享用
Apologies. I said I hope you enjoy your meal.
好
Yeah.
钻头现在在16点处
Drill head now at point 16.
钻头速度加快
Drill head speed increasing.
压力保持在60
Keep pressure at 60.
关闭三号门
Close door 3.
他觉醒了
He is awake.
你说什么
What did you say?
关闭三号门
Close door 3.
托比
Toby.
别回头
Don't turn around.
丹
Dan?
不是丹
That's not Dan.
别看我
Don't look at me.
你是谁
Who are you?
我有很多名字
I have so many names.
我能不能…
If I could...
如果你看向我 你就死定了
If you look at me, you will die.
你是谁
But who are you?
我就在你后面 托比
I'm behind you, Toby.
就在你身后
I'm right behind you.
别看 别看我
Don't look. Don't look at me.
看一眼 你就死定了
One look and you will die.
我正在伸手 托比
I'm reaching out, Toby.
很接近
I'm so close.
别回头
Don't turn around.
哦 我能碰到你
Oh, I can touch you.
不
No.
扎克 出问题了吗
Zack, we got a problem?
司空见惯了
No more than usual.
斯卡勒星系在燃烧 也许值得一看
Got the Scarlet System burning up. Might be worth a look.
你们也许想看看这个
You might want to see this.
历史性的一刻
Moment in history.
那里
There,
在边缘上
on the edge.
那片红云
That red cloud.
那曾经是斯卡勒星系
That used to be the Scarlet System.
普鲁希的家乡
Home to the Pallushi.
闪耀了十亿年的灿烂文明
A mighty civilization spanning a billion years
永远消失了
disappearing forever.
他们的行星和太阳都被吞噬了
Their planets and suns consumed.
女士们 先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
我们见证了它的消亡
we have witnessed its passing.
不 能开着吗
No, could you leave it open?
就一会儿
Just for a bit.
我不会发疯的 我保证
I won't go mad, I promise.
你怎么知道
How would you know?
斯古蒂 检查密封舱
Scooti, check the lockdown.
杰佛逊 关闭空气阻隔舱
Jefferson, sign off the airlock seals for me.
开启18号门
Open door 18.
我看过一些电影
I've seen films and things, yeah?
说黑洞通向另一个宇宙
They say black holes are like gateways to another universe.
关闭18号门
Close door 18.
那一个不是
Not that one.
它只会吞噬
It just eats.
离家太远了
A long way from home.
往那边看
Go that way,
右转 继续走
turn right, keep going for, erm...
大约五百年
about 500 years
就能回到地球
and you'll reach the Earth.
没有信号
No signal.
这是我们第一次远离信号区
That's first time we've gone out of range.
听着 即使我能…
Mind you, even if I could...
我该怎么跟她说
What would I tell her?
你能再造一个塔迪斯吗
Can you build another Tardis?
他们是生长出来的 不是造出来的
They were grown, not built.
随着我的母星一起消失了
And with my home planet gone,
我们困在这儿了
we're kind of stuck.
还不算太糟 至少他们可以载我们一程
Well, it could be worse. This lot said they'd give us a lift.
然后呢
And then what?
我不知道
I don't know.
找一个星球
Find a planet.
找份工作 好好生活
Get a job. You live your life
和其他人一样
same as the rest of the universe.
我得安顿下来
I'd have to settle down.
找栋房子之类的
Get a house or something.
一栋有门和其它东西房子 还有地毯
A proper house with... doors and things. Carpets.
我 住在房子里
Me, living in a house!
我说…那…那真是太可怕了
Now, that... That... That is terrifying.
你得按揭买房
You'd have to get a mortgage.
不  - 是的
No! Oh, yes.
让我死吧 就这样 到此结束
I'm dying. That's it, I am dying. It is all over.
我呢 我也得找间房子
What about me? I'd have to get one, too.
我不知道
I don't know,
也许是同一间 我们俩可以…
could be the same one. We could both...
合住
share.
也许不 随便吧 我不知道
Or not. Whatever. I don't know.
各种…总之 到时候再说
All sorts of... Anyway... We'll see.
我向杰琪保证过 一定会带你回家
I promised Jackie I would always take you back home.
每个人最终都会离开家
Everyone leaves home in the end.
但不是困在这里
Not to end up stuck here.
是啊 但是和你在一起 没这么糟
Yeah, but stuck with you, that's not so bad.
是吗 - 是的
Yeah? - Yes.
他觉醒了
He is awake.
晚上好
Evening.
只是我们
Only us.
神秘小夫妻
The mysterious couple.
你们好吗 还习惯吗
How are you, then? Settling in?
抱歉 开门见山
Yeah, sorry, straight to business.
这些"怪奇" 他们怎么交流
The Ood, how do they communicate?
互相之间
I mean, with each other?
噢 心灵感应
Oh, just empaths.
有一种低级感应场连接着它们
There's a low-level telepathic field connecting them.
这对他们的智力倒没多少帮助
Not that that does them much good.
它们基本就是群聚种族 就像牛羊
They're basically a herd race, like cattle.
这种感应场可以接收信息吗
This telepathic field, can it pick up messages?
因为我们吃饭时 有个"怪奇"说了一些…
'Cause I was having dinner and one of the Oods said something...
"奇怪"的话
Well, odd.
一个"奇怪"的"怪奇"
Hmm. An odd Ood.
还有刚才我又收到了一些…
And then I got something else
就在我的…通讯器上
on my...communicator thing.
别担心
Well, be fair.
整个星系在我们头顶燃烧
We've got whole star systems burning up around us,
会有各种游离的信号
there's all sorts of stray transmissions.
也许什么都不是
Probably nothing.
听着 如果出错了 电脑会显示
Look, if there was something wrong, it would show.
我们监控着感应场
We monitor the telepathic field.
这是照顾它们的唯一方法
It's the only way to look after them.
它们太蠢了
They're so stupid.
连生病都不告诉我们
They don't even tell us when they're ill.
监控感应场 是这个吗
Monitor the field, that's this thing. Yeah.
是的 不过我说了 是低级别感应
But like I said, it's low-level telepathy.
它们只有五级感应
They only register Basic 5.
这可不是五级
Well, that's not Basic 5.
是十
10.
二十
20.
上升到三十了
They've gone up to Basic 30.
不可能
But they can't.
博士 看他们
Doctor, the Ood.
三十级别说明什么
What does Basic 30 mean?
说明他们正在大叫 头脑里在叫喊
Well, it means that they're shouting, screaming inside their heads.
或者有什么在叫喊它们
Or something is shouting at them.
可这是从哪儿来的
But where is it coming from?
它说了什么
What is it saying?
它跟你说了什么
What did it say to you?
说了些什么"怪兽" "深渊"
Something about the Beast and the Pit.
你的通讯器呢 它说什么了
What about your communicator? What did that say?
"他觉醒了"
He is awake.
而你们要侍奉它
And you will worship him.
什么情况
What the hell?
他觉醒了
He is awake.
你们要侍奉它
And you will worship him.
侍奉谁
Worship who?
谁在和你们说话
Who's talking to you?
是谁
Who is it?
托比 我拿到你的经费表了
Toby, I've got your expenditure.
开启41号门
Open door 41.
关闭41号门
Close door 41.
四十一
41?
关闭40号门
Close door 40.
计算机 你开启了41号门吗
Computer, did you open and close door 41?
确认
Confirmed.
但那是空气阻隔舱 为什么开启它
But that's the airlock. Why would you open the airlock?
现在是晚上模式 不能出去
It's the night shift, we're not allowed outside.
有人出去了吗
Has someone gone out?
确认
Confirmed.
是谁
But who was it?
无法确认
Cannot confirm.
好吧 等一下
Okay. Right, hold on, I know.
谁的宇航服在使用中
Tell me whose spacesuit has been logged out.
没有人的宇航服在使用中
No spacesuit has been logged out.
这不合理 出去外面不能不穿…
You're not making any sense. You can't go outside without...
扎克 41号门出问题了
Zack, I think we've got a breakdown on door 41.
它说有人出去到星球表面了
It's saying somebody's gone outside onto the planet's surface.
扎克
Zack?
计算机 故障检索
Computer, trace fault.
无故障
There is no fault.
告诉我 谁过了这道门
Tell me who went through that door?
他觉醒了
He is awake.
什么
What?
他觉醒了
He is awake.
这是什么意思
What's that supposed to mean'?
它沐浴在黑色的阳光下
He bathes in the black sun.
托比
Toby.
外面没有空气 没有…
There's no air, there's no...
不 停下 你不能
No, stop it! You can't be!
开启40号门
Open door 40!
紧急情况 墙体破裂
Emergency hull breach. Emergency hull breach.
哪个区域
Which section?
所有人撤离11至13号舱 墙体破裂
Everyone, evacuate 11 to 13. We've got a breach.
基地敞开了 重复一遍 基地敞开了
The Base is open. Repeat, the Base is open.
开启19号门
Open door 19.
关闭19号门
Close door 19.
氧气带正在减小 我们将失去氧气
I can't contain the oxygen field. We're gonna lose it.
快 不要停
Come on! Keep moving!
还有你 小子 进来
And you, too, sunshine!
大家没事吧  - 裂缝已修复
Everyone all right? - Breach sealed.
出什么事了 怎么回事
What happened? What was it?
墙体破裂 我们暴露在外
Hull breach. We were open to the elements.
晚一两分钟 我们就得近距离考察黑洞了
Another couple of minutes and we'd have been inspecting that black hole at close quarters.
那不是震荡 怎么回事
That wasn't a quake. What caused it?
我们失去11至13区了
We've lost sections 11 to 13.
大家没事吧
Everyone all right?
所有人都在 除了斯古蒂
We've got everyone here except Scooti.
斯古蒂 请回复
Scooti, report.
斯古蒂·曼尼斯特
Scooti Manista,
这是命令 请回复
this is an order, report.
她没事
She's  all right.
我找到她的生物芯片了 她在三号生活区
I've picked up her biochip. She's in Habitation 3.
最好去看看 她没回应
Better go and check if she's not responding.
可能晕倒了
She might be unconscious.
想想这个如何：我们逃过一劫
But how about that, eh? We survived.
三号生活区
Habitation 3.
走吧 这不是我的作风 不过我们该喝一杯
Come on. I don't often say this, but I think we could all do with a drink.
走吧
Come on.
出什么事了
What happened?
我也不知道 我在工作
I don't know. I was working and then
记不清了 到处都是噪音
I can't remember. All that noise.
房间崩裂 没有空气
The room was falling apart. There was no air.
来吧 起来
Come on, up you get.
去吃点一号蛋白质
Come and have some Protein One.
你入乡随俗了
You've gone native.
别挑剔了 还不错
Oi, don't knock it, it's nice.
一号蛋白质再掺点三号
Protein One with just a dash of Three.
检查一下四号生活区
Check out Habitation 4.
没有踪迹 但她的芯片显示在这儿
There's no sign of her, but the biochip says she's in this area.
斯古蒂 听见请回话
Scooti. If you can hear this, please respond.
六号生活区
Habitation 6...
不在这里
Nowhere here.
扎克 有麻烦了
Zack, we've got a problem.
找不到斯古蒂
Scooti's still missing.
但电脑显示在三号生活区
But it says Habitation 3.
我正在这里呢 我告诉你
Well, that's where I am and I'm telling you,
她不在这儿
she's not here.
我找到她了
I've found her.
天哪
Oh, my God.
抱歉 真的很抱歉
Sorry. I'm so sorry.
船长
Captain...
报告
report
队员斯古蒂·曼尼斯特 PKD
Officer Scootori Manista, PKD...
牺牲
deceased.
公元43000 1月2日
43K 2.1.
她才二十岁
She was 20.
二十岁
20 years old.
最壮烈的死
For how should man die better
莫过于在绝境中
Than facing fearful odds
为父辈的英魂
For the ashes of his father
为神圣的信仰
And the temples
献出自己的生命
of his gods?
停下来了
It's stopped.
那是什么
What was that?
是什么
What was it?
钻井机
The drill.
钻探停止了
We've stopped drilling.
我们成功了
We've made it.
到达零点
Point 0.
所有闲置的怪奇限制行动
All non-essential Oods to be confined.
太空舱确认 设备运行正常
Capsule established. All systems functioning.
采矿队离开
The mineshaft is go.
各系统联机
Bring systems online now.
报告长官 我自愿加入远征队
Reporting as a volunteer for the expeditionary force.
博士 这违反了每一条规定
Doctor, this is breaking every single protocol.
我们甚至不知道你是谁
We don't even know who you are.
但你们信任我 不是吗
Yeah, but you trust me, don't you?
而且你不能让艾达一个人去
And you can't let Ida go down there on her own.
来吧
Go on,
看着我的眼睛 是的
look me in the eye. Yes, you do.
我能看见 信任
I can see it. Trust.
我应该下去
I should be going down.
船长不必身先士卒
The captain doesn't lead the mission.
他留在这里 运筹帷幄
He stays here, in charge.
这儿用不着什么指挥 不是吗
Not much good here, am I?
各就各位 两分钟后下去
Positions! We're going down in two!
所有人 各就各位
Everyone, positions!
杰佛逊先生 各系统全力以赴
Mr Jefferson, I want maximum systems...
氮氧平衡 重力稳定
Oxygen, nitro balance, gravity.
我上次穿这身是很久以前的事了
It's ages since I wore one of these.
我要宇航服完整无缺地回来 明白吗
I want that spacesuit back in one piece. You got that?
是 长官
Yes, sir.
有趣的是 我们那个时代的人都以为
It's funny 'cause people back home think that
太空旅行会变得轻而易举
space travel is gonna be all...whizzing about
瞬间转移 反重力
and teleports, anti-gravity.
根本不是这样 是吗 很艰苦
But it's not, is it? It's tough.
回来再找你
I'll see you later.
我先来找你
Not if I see you first.
你们留在这里
You will remain here.
这条命令优先于任何其它命令
No command can override this.
明白了吗
Have you got that?
只能听从我的指示
My instructions only.
太空舱准备
Capsule active.
倒计时 十
Counting down, in ten,
九
nine,
八 七 六
eight, seven, six,
五 四 三
five, four, three,
二 一
two, one,
释放
release.
你们已经离开了氧气带 全靠你们自己了
You've gone beyond the oxygen field. You're on your own.
别忘了呼吸
Don't forget to breathe.
调整呼吸
Breathing is good.
洛斯 放下通讯器
Rose, stay off the comm.
没门
No chance.
博士
Doctor?
博士 你没事吧
Doctor, are you all right?
艾达 请回答
Ida, report to me.
博士
Doctor?
一切正常 我们顺利抵达
It's all right. We've made it.
正踏出太空舱
Heading out of the capsule now.
下面情况怎么样
What's it like down there?
很难描述
It's hard to tell.
有点像洞穴 洞窟 规模很大
Some sort of cave. Cavern. It's massive.
这个或许有用
Well, this should help.
重力球
Gravity globe.
那真是…
That's...
真是…
哦 天哪 真是太美了
Oh, my God. That's beautiful.
洛斯
Rose...
告诉托比
you can tell Toby...
我们发现了他所说的文明
we've found his civilization.
托比 听上去你有工作要做了
Oi, Toby, sounds like you've got plenty of work.
很好
Good, good.
集中注意 执行任务
Concentrate now, people. Keep on the mission.
艾达 能量源呢
Ida, what about the power source?
接近了
We're close.
能量信号指向北面
Energy signature indicates north-
西北 上面能收到图像吗
northwest. Are you getting pictures up there?
干扰太多
There's too much interference.
全交给你了
We're in your hands.
我们走了这么远了
Well, we've come this far.
没有回头路了
There's no turning back.
你非得这么说吗
Oh, did you have to?
"没有回头路" 这话糟糕透了
No turning back? That's almost as bad as,
就像"任何事都不会出错"
"Nothing can possibly go wrong"
"这将是沃尔福德最棒的圣诞节"
or "This is gonna be the best Christmas Walford's ever had."
你说完了吗
Have you finished?
说完了
Yeah. Finished.
船长 怪奇出现了一些情况
Captain, sir, there's something happening with the Ood.
它们在干什么
What are they doing?
目不转睛地盯着我
They're staring at me.
我命令它们停止 但它们不听
I've told them to stop, but they won't.
丹尼 你是个大人了
Danny, you're a big boy,
被盯一下没什么
I think you can take being stared at.
但感应场的读数
But the telepathic field, sir,
已经达到100了
it's at Basic 100.
我检查过了
I've checked.
没有故障
There isn't any fault.
的确是100
It's definitely 100.
这不可能
But that's impossible.
100意味着什么
What's Basic 100 mean?
它们应该死了
They should be dead.
100是脑死亡
Basic 100 is brain death.
但它们很安全 有什么动作吗
But they're safe? They're not actually moving?
没有 长官
No, sir.
继续观察
Keep watching them.
杰佛逊 继续守着怪奇
And you, Jefferson, keep a guard on the Ood.
举起武器
Officer at arms.
你不能在这里开枪 万一打穿了墙怎么办
You can't fire a gun in here. What if you hit a wall?
15发子弹 只对有机物有效
Firing Stock 15, only impacts upon organics.
继续留意 守住它们
Keep watch. Guard them.
是的
Yes, sir.
上面一切都好吗
is everything all right up there?
很好
Yeah, yeah.
没问题 好极了
It's fine. Great.
我们有发现
We've found something.
看上去是金属 像某种封印
It looks like metal, like some sort of seal.
我有种不好的感觉 这可能是"活板门"
I've got a nasty feeling the word might be "trap door".
不是什么好东西 我从来不喜欢"活板门"这东西
Not a good word, trap door. Never met a trap door I liked.
外圈雕刻着某种符号
The edge is covered with those symbols.
能打开吗
Do you think it opens?
那就是活板门会做的事
That's what trap doors tend to do.
活板门又不能判断是非
Trap door doesn't do it justice.
这东西很大 扎克
It's massive, Zack.
直径大约30英尺
About 30 feet in diameter.
有办法打开吗
Any way of opening it?
不知道 找不到任何机关
Don't know. I can't see any sort of mechanism.
我猜那些文字会告诉我们怎么做
I suppose that's the writing. It would tell us what to do.
但这些文字无法翻译
The letters that defy translation.
托比 你有办法破译它吗
Toby, did you get anywhere with decoding it?
托比 我们需要知道 那些文字有什么意思吗
Toby, they need to know. That lettering, does it make any sort of sense?
我知道
I know what it says.
告诉他们
Then tell them.
你什么时候破解的
When did you work that out?
这无关紧要 告诉他们
It doesn't matter, just tell them!
那是怪兽的语言
These are the words of the Beast.
他觉醒了
And he has woken.
他是黑暗中跳动的心脏
He is the heart that beats in the darkness.
他是永不停息的鲜血
He is the blood that will never cease.
现在 他将崛起
And now he will rise.
长官 请后退 后退
Officer, you will stand down. Stand down!
什么 他做了什么
What is it? What's he done?
出什么事了
What's happening?
洛斯 出什么事了
Rose, what's going on?
杰佛逊 请回话
Jefferson, report.
回话
Report!
长官 你危及大家安全了
Officer, you have compromised security.
后退 不许动
You will stand down and be confined.
马上
Immediately!
杰佛逊先生 告诉我
Mr. Jefferson, tell me, sir...
你妻子原谅你了吗
did your wife ever forgive you?
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you mean.
告诉你个秘密
Let me tell you a secret.
她一直没有原谅你
She never did.
长官
Officer,
请后退 不许动
you will stand down and be confined.
否则如何
Or what?
红色警报情况下 我有权射杀你
Or under the strictures of Condition Red, I am authorised to shoot you.
你能杀多少
But how many can you kill?
我们是怪兽的军团
We are the legion of the Beast.
洛斯 怎么回事 洛斯
Rose, what is it? Rose?
我要上去
I'm going back up.
请回话
Report!
杰佛逊 回话
Jefferson, report!
有人回话吗
Someone report!
军团人数众多
The legion shall be many
军团人口稀少
and the legion shall be few.
是怪奇
It's the Ood.
长官 我们的牲畜被感染了
Sir, we have contamination of the livestock.
博士 不知道怎么回事 它们好像被附身了
Doctor, I don't know what it is. It's like they're possessed.
它们不听我们的
They won't listen to us.
它早已融入了你们的生活
He has woven himself in the fabric of your life
早至时间诞生之初
since the dawn of time.
有人叫它"地狱" 有人叫它"苦果"
Some may call him Abbadon. Some may call him Krop Tor.
有人叫它"撒旦" 或 "路西法"
Some may call him Satan or Lucifer.
船长 怪奇失控了
They're out of control.
或"绝望之主"
...the King of Despair,
不朽的王子 黑夜的缔造者
the Deathless Prince. The Bringer of Night.
这些话语 将会让它重获自由
And these are the words that shall set him free.
到门那边去
Back up to the door!
我将要显形
I am become manifest.
快走
Move quickly!
我将走进光明
I shall walk in the light.
去门那儿
To the door!
我的军队将蜂拥而至 席卷全宇宙
And my legions will swarm across worlds.
博士
Doctor,
它打开了
it's opening!
我们在移动
We're moving!
一切都在移动 整个行星都在移动
The whole thing's moving, the planet's moving.
我是罪恶 是诱惑
I am the sin and the temptation
我是欲望
and the desire.
我是痛苦 是伤亡 是绝望
I am the pain and the loss and the death of hope.
把门打开
Get that door open!
引力场正在消失
The gravity field, it's going!
我们要脱离轨道了
We're losing orbit!
我们要掉进黑洞了
We're gonna fall into the black hole!
我曾被永远禁锢
I have been imprisoned for eternity.
但到此为止
But no more.
门已封闭
Door sealed.
深渊开启了
The Pit is open
我自由了
and I am free!
是怪奇 他们疯了
It's the Ood. They've gone mad.
博士 听得见吗
Doctor, can you hear me?
博士 艾达 在吗
Doctor, Ida, are you there?
丹尼 右转
Danny, turn right.
它在利用你的原始恐惧
That thing is playing on very basic fears.
缆绳断了
The cable's snapped.
出去
Get out!
你们会死 而我将永生
You will die and I will live.